Hey Keshan, congratulations.
>> Thank you. Thank you. I appreciate it.
>> Yep. Yep. I read that you modeled your
game after Fred Warner. Why is he maybe
one of your favorite players and what
have you tried to draw from his his
play?
>> Yeah. I think, you know, if you're any
type of linebacker, I want to be, you
know, somebody great like Fred Warner,
you know, one of the best linebackers in
the league. And, you know, everything
that he does, you know, from off the
field to on the field is just elite. And
you look at, you know, a linebacker
that's a game changer. you know, anytime
he's going to get punched that ball out,
he's going to get interceptions, you
know, he's going to be disruptive in the
run game. So, just, you know, his
overall disruptiveness is something
that, you know, I want to take away from
him. How is how is he getting all these
forced fumbles and, you know, getting in
passing lanes. So, just watching his
game and, you know, a lot of it's just a
reflection of how much time he puts into
the game, watching film and everything,
you know, playing playing before the
snap. So, um, you know, a great guy to
watch film. when you have 14 tackles for
loss and seven sacks, how does that come
to be in one season for a linebacker?
>> Just watch a lot of film, you know,
understand what's going on before um you
know, the ball snap like I was saying
about Fred, but um you know, I just it's
something that I wanted to do, you know,
walking into this past season was I
needed to play behind the line of
scrimmage just a little bit more and you
know, I was you know, blessed to be, you
know, have a great D line that was able
to hold some blocks for me to, you know,
go down there and run through some
lanes. So, um, just overall just, you
know, the amount of work I put in just
led to those 14, uh, tackles for loss.
>> Courtney,
>> Ean, what were your interactions like
with the Bears either at the combine or
after that?
>> Yeah, actually, it was funny. I was just
talking to my agent about it. We uh, we
didn't really meet with the Bears too
much. Um, I remember at the combine, it
was great. Great. You know, you have
seven minutes with them or 15 minutes
total. Um, so it was quick. I mean, you
tell them who you are, who you're about
as a person, and then you talk a little
bit of football. But, um, you know, it
was one of the, you know, lesser teams
that I talked to. So, it's, you know, a
great opportunity for me and, you know,
me and my family are just happy at the
end of the day to, you know, be able to,
you know, go right down the road to
Chicago.
>> Sure. And did you, I mean, you grew up
in Missouri, is that right?
>> Correct. Right outside of Kansas City.
>> Who was your team growing up? Were you a
Bears fan? Were you a Chiefs fan?
>> Yeah, I mean, I watched I watched Denver
growing up. A lot of my family members
are Denver fans. So, you know, I was a
Denver fan for, you know, quite some
time, but I think once you start playing
football, you just become a fan of, you
know, players, and there's a lot of
players around the league that, you
know, I watch and a big fan of.
>> Sean,
>> hey, Keshan, congrats, man. Um,
>> thank you.
>> Can you sort of just take us through
your special teams experience and and
how you think you can contribute uh here
in Chicago on special teams?
>> Yeah, 100%. you know, that's the first
thing that I'm going to be doing when I
get into the building is, you know,
meeting with the special teams
coordinator and, you know, understanding
the schematics of it. I look, you know,
at myself and I look at a guy that was
able to lead, you know, multiple
defenses for, you know, multiple amount
of years. So, going into the league, I
know that's going to be a priority for
myself is, you know, walking in and, you
know, be able being able to, you know,
handle special teams, not just, you
know, for myself, but also the other
guys around me. So, something I'm super
excited about and, you know, I think,
you know, my play as a linebacker is
something that, you know, translates
pretty well to special teams.
Dan
John,
>> a little big picture question. When and
and why did football become really
really important to you?
>> Um, I started playing football about
nine years old and it was just something
I fell in love with. You know, it takes
you away from everything else that's
going on in the world. Kind of gives
you, you know, something to do that's
bigger than yourself. You build, you
know, tons of relationships. You're a
part of, you know, a bunch of different
groups of guys that, you know, you are
going to know for the rest of your life.
So everything that comes with football
and the you know opportunities it it's
provided me with is just unbelievable
and you know something you know it's
easy to wake up to. I love you know the
game of football putting all the work in
the extra work everything it takes is
you know just something I truly love.
>> What's the setup you got going on today
with uh with just the draft celebration
who all is with you and what's it been
like?
>> Uh yeah we're down in my grandparents
basement in Richmond, Missouri where I
grew up. Um, but the whole family is out
here, some friends, you know, just just
close circle here and um, you know,
we're super excited to join a great
program.
>> Last two, Adam.
>> Kean, how did playing quarterback maybe
help you as a as a linebacker?
>> You understand the game level? You know,
I was, you know, high school
quarterback. I thought I was going to go
to college, play quarterback. That
wasn't the case. But, um, you know, I
understand what's going on in front of
me a lot. I can, you know, acknowledge,
you know, how offense is going to attack
us, whether, you know, we're in a
different coverage. You know, you, you
understand what they're going to do, do
do and, um, it just allows me to play
fast and, you know, learn the game fast.
You just the things the amount of things
it took to, you know, be a successful
quarterback just translates over to
linebacker when it comes to work ethic
and things like that.
>> Okay, never mind. Last two. Courtney,
then Dan,
>> um, real quick, just going back to the
question on special teams. I know you
played so much on defense, um,
especially the last two years. How much
special teams experience do you have?
Like were you doing it much at Arizona
State?
>> No, I didn't I didn't I didn't really
play special teams at all, but it's
something we always practice. I was
always on the depth chart. Um it's not
like I was, you know, taking breaks,
stepping over to the other practice
field. No, I'm I'm involved in special
teams. So, we're doing all the drills,
all those things. And I think, you know,
I'm in a great position where I can, you
know, go play linebacker, but also play
special teams. everything that you do in
terms of, you know, using your hands and
having a base, using your footwork as a
linebacker translates over to, you know,
special teams, especially when it comes
to tackling and fitting up on people.
>> Dan,
>> you the Bear Scout was telling us a
little bit about the the commendation
you got for your weight room work. What
all goes into to winning the Iron Devil
award, not once, but twice.
Yeah, it was actually I think I won it,
you know, I was there for four
semesters. So, we it's a semester award,
so I won it three out of the four, four
out of four, one of two, but you know,
just super blessed to have that strength
staff, you know, just translate, you
know, my game, my physique, you know,
how I looked off the field and what I
was doing from, you know, my eating
habits and recovery habits. Just, you
know, unbelievable support staff over
there in the in the weight room. But,
you know, like you said, it was just the
amount of work I put in ultimately. you
know, I was I was there morning and
night, you know, outside outside of just
our organized uh lifting sessions. So,
just the amount of work that I put in
and, you know, I'm a strong believer in
work works and you're going to get
whatever you put in, you know, you're
going to get out of it.
>> Adam,
>> Keshan, other than quarterback and
linebacker, did I read you were an all
state punter as well?
>> Yeah. Yeah, I I punted the ball. I I
learned how to, you know, get the
turnover and do the spiral and um you
know, something that it's easy to work
on. you can go out there pre-practice,
mid-practice, you know, whenever. You
can just go out there and kick the ball.
So, it's something, you know, I actually
enjoy doing. So, um it's, you know,
definitely something exciting to talk
about.
>> Okay, last one. Pat,
>> what's it like being one of 10 kids?
>> Oh, it's great. You know, you got, you
know, relationships all over the place.
Um, you know, blessed to have all my
siblings, a bunch of girls, and a couple
brothers. But um it's you know great and
something you know I'm just blessed to
be doing this and you know just be a guy
that they can look up to and you know
rely on that's that's the biggest thing.
>> Where are you on the list? Uh so there I
have four older siblings and then five
younger.